There are two sides to the American dream.
American Gangster is a drama, crime film directed by Ridley Scott.
Loosely based on the criminal career of Frank Lucas, a gangster from La Grange, North Carolina, who smuggled heroin into the United States on
American service planes returning from the Vietnam War, before being detained by a task force led by Newark Detective Richie Roberts.
Frank Lucas, played by Denzel Washington.
Richie Roberts, played by Russell Crowe.
Detective Trupo, played by Josh Brolin.
Huey Lucas, played by Chiwetel Ejiofor.
Nicky Barnes, played by Cuba Gooding Jr..
Eva, played by Lymari Nadal.
American Gangster is a 2007 American biographical crime drama film directed
and produced by Ridley Scott and written by Steven Zaillian.
The film is loosely based on the criminal career of Frank Lucas, a gangster from La Grange, North Carolina who smuggled heroin into the United States on
American service planes returning from the Vietnam War, before being detained by a task force led by Newark Detective Richie Roberts.
The film stars Denzel Washington and Russell Crowe, with co-stars Ted Levine, John Ortiz,
Josh Brolin, Chiwetel Ejiofor, Ruby Dee, Lymari Nadal and Cuba Gooding Jr.
Development for the film initially began in 2000, when Universal Pictures and Imagine Entertainment
purchased the rights to a New York magazine story about the rise and fall of Lucas.
Two years later, screenwriter Steven Zaillian
introduced a 170-page scriptment to Scott.
Original production plans were to commence in Toronto for budget purposes;
however, production eventually relocated permanently to New York City.
Because of the film's rising budget Universal canceled production in 2004.
After negotiations with Terry George, it was later
revived with Scott at the helm in March 2005.
Principal photography commenced over a period of five months from July to December 2006;
filming took place throughout New York City and concluded in Thailand.
American Gangster premiered in New York on October 20, 2007, and
was released in the United States on November 2.
The film was well received by critics and grossed over $266 million worldwide.
Many of the people portrayed, including Roberts and Lucas, have stated that the film took much creative license with
the story, and three former DEA agents sued Universal claiming the agency's portrayal was demoralizing.
American Gangster was nominated for twenty-one awards, including two Oscar nominations for Best Art Direction and Best Supporting Actress
for Ruby Dee, who also won a Screen Actors Guild Award for Outstanding Performance by a Female Actor in a Supporting Role.
The film explores themes of new york city, vietnam,
drug smuggling, society, gangster.
The tone is emotional and intense.